我从 CSS 中学到的第一个技巧之一
One of the very first tricks that I learned with CSS
是如何在浏览器中居中页面。
was how to center a page inside of the browser.
所以回到过去，
So back in the day,
许多寻呼机没有居中，我发现它真的很酷
many pagers were not centered and I found it really cool
我们可以很容易地在浏览器中将页面居中
that we could very easily center a page in a browser
使用一个非常简单的技巧。所以现在让我
using a very simple trick. And so let me now
在此视频中与您分享这个非常棒的技巧。
share that really nice trick with you in this video.
现在，我们需要做的第一件事
Now, the very first thing that we need to do
为了完成这个技巧是
in order to pull off this trick is to
将我们所有的内容放入一个容器元素中，
put all of our content into a container element,
因为否则，如果我们不这样做，
because otherwise, if we don't do that,
那么实际上在窗口中居中的是什么？
then what is there actually to center in the window?
所以我的意思是现在，随着我们不断调整大小
So what I mean is that right now, as we keep resizing
浏览器窗口，实际上所有的内容
the browser window, all of the content actually
从一侧延伸到另一侧。
stretches from one side to the other.
所以没有内容可以居中
So there is no content there to center
在浏览器的中心，对吧？
in the center of the browser, right?
所以我们首先需要一个容器和那个容器
So we first need a container and that container
然后需要一定的宽度。
then needs a certain width.
所以让我们把所有这些都放在一个盒子里
So let's put all of this into a box and
这个框不需要有任何特殊含义。
this box doesn't need to have any special meaning.
所以我们在这里不需要语义 HTML 元素。
So we don't need a semantic HTML element here.
所以我们可以简单地使用 div 元素。
And so we can simply use a div element.
现在这个不应该在这里关闭，
Now this one should not close here,
但它应该在身体结束之前关闭。
but it should close right before the end of the body.
所以它从那里开始
So it starts right there
我们只在页脚之后关闭它。
and we close it only here after the footer.
现在当我保存它时，
And now as I save it,
所有缩进都应该自动修复
all the indentation should automatically get fixed
确实如此，很好。所以这是一件非常好的事情
and it did, nice. So this is a really nice thing
关于更漂亮，所以当我们不断添加其他元素时，
about prettier, so when we keep adding other elements,
然后所有的缩进都会自动修复，
then all the indentation will automatically get fixed,
这真的非常有帮助。
which is really, really helpful.
那么在这里，我们需要给我们一个名字
Then here, we need to give us a name
我喜欢使用容器的名称。
and I like to use the name of container.
让我们复制该类并在此处设置样式。
Let's copy that class and style it here.
正如我所说，现在我们实际上需要给予
And as I was saying, now we actually need to give
这个容器有一个宽度，因为
this container a width because
否则就没有什么可居中的了。
otherwise there is not really anything to center.
所以让我们从 700 像素开始
So let's start with 700 pixels
稍后我会扩大一点。
and I'll make it a bit wider later.
好的。
Okay.
所以我们现在有这个 700 像素的宽度。
So we have this width of 700 pixels now.
所以你会看到现在这个元素的宽度。
So you'll see it that now the width of this element.
所以这里的标题，
So this header here,
这是容器的子元素是
which is a child element of the container is
现在也只有 702 像素。
now only 702 pixels as well.
再说一遍，这里的 div 的宽度是 700，
So again, this div here has a width of 700,
所以我们可以在这里看到。
so we can see that here.
所以现在的子元素，
And so now the child elements,
里面当然不能大于
which are inside of it can of course not be bigger than
那。所以它们只能和容器元素一样大。
that. So they can only be as large as the container element.
因此，这个也是 600 像素宽
And so therefore this one is also a 600 pixels wide
或者实际上是 700。所以这是 620 加 40 加 40。
or actually 700. So that's 620 plus 40 plus 40.
好的。
Okay.
所以这与继承或其他东西无关
So this has nothing to do like with inheritance or something
像那样。相反，它只是逻辑
like that. Instead it is simply the logic that
子元素永远不能比父元素宽
the child element can never be wider than the parent
元素。所以如果父元素是700，
element. And so if the parent element is 700,
那么所有其他人也将是700。
then all the others are going to be 700 as well.
所以这个例如是 700 和 h2 也是如此，
So this one for example is 700 and the h2 as well,
等等等等。
and so on and so forth.
对，当然图片也是如此，
Right, the same here goes for the image of course,
这是父母的100％。
which is 100% of the parent.
所以现在我们继续做大
And so now as we keep making this bigger
这个 700 像素的容器在这里，67
this 700 pixel container here,
始终保持在左侧。
always keep staying on the left side.
所以现在作为最后一步，
And so now as a final step,
我们需要将这个容器元素居中
we need to center this container element
浏览器内部。
inside of the browser.
这就是真正的技巧。
And so that is the actual trick.
所以给容器宽度是第一部分，
So giving the container width is part one,
现在第二部分是在左边添加一些边距
and now part two is to add some margins to the left
和容器的右侧。
and to the right of the container.
所以我们可以说margin left，然后设置为auto，
So we can say margin left and then set it to auto,
代表自动。
which stands for automatic.
右边距也是自动的。
And margin to the right also automatic.
所以这意味着左边的边距需要
So what this means is that the margin on the left needs to
与右侧的边距相同。
be the same than the margin on the right side.
它们都应该自动计算
And they should both be calculated automatically
通过浏览器。
by the browser.
因此，这将意味着会有一个余量
And so therefore this will mean that there will be a margin
在左边和右边，
on the left and on the right,
这将是完全相同的大小。
which will be exactly the same size.
因此，结果，
And therefore, as a result,
容器将在身体内部看起来居中。
the container will look centered inside of the body.
所以基本上在浏览器内部。
So basically inside of the browser.
因此，如果我们给我们一个安全的，那么它确实有效。
So if we give us a safe , then it does actually work.
伟大的。
Great.
这是太棒了。
This is fantastic.
所以当我们调整大小时，让我们看看，
So as we resize, let's see,
然后左边和右边的边距不断增长。
then the margin on the left and on the right keep growing.
他们基本上一直给我们一种错觉，即
And they keep giving us basically this illusion that the
页面完全居中
page is completely centered
使容器居中。
so that the container is centered.
所以如果我现在检查这个并去容器，
So if I inspect this now and go to the container,
然后在这里，我可以看到边距是现在，
then here, I can see that the margin is right now,
两边180。
180 on both sides.
如果我调整这个大小，
And if I resize this,
然后你会看到现在它只是例如，
then you see that now it is only for example,
每边72个半。
72 and a half on each side.
所以再一次，两边都是一样的
So again, it is the same on both sides
因为两边都是自动的。
because it is auto on both sides.
而auto表示浏览器会自动
And auto means that the browser will automatically
算出宽度。
figure out the width.
好的。
Okay.
现在这里实际上我希望这是 800 像素，
Now here actually I want this to be 800 pixels,
但我之前把它放小了一点，
but I put it a bit smaller before,
因为如果我们再这样说，我们实际上不能，
because if we then put it like this, we can actually not,
什么也看不见。所以它看起来并不居中，
not see anything. So it doesn't look centered,
但当然，如果我们继续扩大窗口，
but of course, if we keep growing the window,
那么现在整个专栏都很好地居中，对吧？
then now this entire column is nicely centered, right?
所以这是一个非常棒的技巧。
So this is a really great trick.
我记得在那天，就像 15 年前一样，
And I remember back in the day, like way over 15 years ago,
当我发现这个技巧时，我真的很高兴。
I was really happy when I discovered this trick.
现在，刚刚结束，
Now, just to finish,
我们也可以再次将serie写成速记，
we can also write the serie as a shorthand once again,
这实际上更常见。
which is actually even more common.
所以现在顶部和底部的边距为零
So the margin at the top and the bottom right now is zero
左右，是自动的。
and left and right, is auto.
这就是速记的第二个值。
And so that is the second value of the shorthand.
所以我们可以摆脱这个。
So we can get rid of this.
好了，让我们再次测试一下。
And there we go, let's test it again.
事实上，它的工作原理是一样的，对吧？
And indeed it had work the same, right?
有了这个，我们完成了这个绝妙的技巧。
And with this, we finished this nice trick.
而且实际上我们完成了这部分
And also actually we finished this part of
关于盒子模型的部分。
the section about the box model.
所以这意味着我们现在已经准备好迎接下一个
And so what this means is that we are now ready for the next
编码挑战的一部分。
part of the coding challenge.
所以在揭露了这个，也许揭露了整个
So after revealing this and maybe revealing this entire
文件，所以它现在的样子
file, so how it looks like right now
在本节的这一部分之后。
after this part of the section.
所以一旦你这样做了，
So once you're done doing that,
那么让我们继续到下一个视频并开始我们的下一个
then let's move on to the next video and start our next
编码挑战。
coding challenge.
所以在那里见。
So see you there.